<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Passwd.Blog</title>
    <link>https://passwd.blog/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Passwd.Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://passwd.blog/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Bash Notes - Things I use often, a nice place to keep a reminder...</title>
      <link>https://passwd.blog/blog/linux-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://passwd.blog/blog/linux-notes/</guid>
      <description>BASH I use a lot of Bash and Powershell scripts, I will update this page mainly as a aide-memoire for usefull scripts and snippets&amp;hellip;
1. Time the execution time of your command or script time yourscript.sh --- or --- start=`date +%s` stuff end=`date +%s` runtime=$((end-start)) --- or --- SECONDS=0 myScript.sh echo $SECONDS  2. Show the current time in a script echo $(date +&amp;quot;%T&amp;quot;)  3. Output of a command to Bash variable For example: Store the number of lines in a file in a Bash variable:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from (Twitter:@jessitron) Jessica Joy Kerr&#39;s Bash to Powershell Twitter Thread</title>
      <link>https://passwd.blog/blog/powershell-notes-from-jessitron/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://passwd.blog/blog/powershell-notes-from-jessitron/</guid>
      <description>Introduction On the 13th of November 2019, someone in my Twitter feel retweeted @jessitron Jessica Joy Kerr&amp;rsquo;s Thread titled:
&amp;ldquo;I sat down to learn enough PowerShell to recreate one of my bash functions.&amp;rdquo;
While I have been using Bash and PowerShell for many years, I learnt quite a few new things and thought I would write it down here for future reference.
Bash to Powershell Long Names PowerShell prefers long names, and it tries to make them generic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PART 1: Hugo: Installation, Setup and publishing to GitHub pages using a custom domain.</title>
      <link>https://passwd.blog/blog/hugo-install-setup-publish-part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://passwd.blog/blog/hugo-install-setup-publish-part1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This post is somewhat meta, it describes my journey installing hugo, setting up Hugo on my authoring machines and publishing the site to GitHub pages using a custom domain.
I will detail both Windows 10 and Ubuntu-19.10 setups.
I found a lot of very good information on the web, but found it a bit fragmented and made a lot of assumptions, especially as far as git knowledge is concerned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PART 2: Hugo: Installation, Setup and publishing to GitHub pages using a custom domain.</title>
      <link>https://passwd.blog/blog/hugo-install-setup-publish-part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://passwd.blog/blog/hugo-install-setup-publish-part2/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is Part 2 of my journey installing hugo, setting up Hugo on my authoring machines and publishing the site to GitHub pages using a custom domain.
I will detail both Windows 10 and Ubuntu-19.10 setups.
Click here for Part 1.
In Part 1  Installing Hugo Configuring Hugo Creating a Hugo Site  Click here for Part 2.
In Part 2  Installing Git Setting up GitHub Setting up Git to work with Hugo Installing a Theme Running the site for the first time Pushing all the code to GitHub  Click here for Part 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PART 3: Hugo: Installation, Setup and publishing to GitHub pages using a custom domain.</title>
      <link>https://passwd.blog/blog/hugo-install-setup-publish-part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://passwd.blog/blog/hugo-install-setup-publish-part3/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is Part 3 of my journey installing hugo, setting up Hugo on my authoring machines and publishing the site to GitHub pages using a custom domain.
I will detail both Windows 10 and Ubuntu-19.10 setups.
Click here for Part 1.
In Part 1  Installing Hugo Configuring Hugo Creating a Hugo Site  Click here for Part 2.
In Part 2  Installing Git Setting up GitHub Setting up Git to work with Hugo Installing a Theme Running the site for the first time Pushing all the code to GitHub  Click here for Part 3.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>